Andrew Paschall

602.615.0610 | paschallandrew@gmail.com | Phoenix, AZ

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andrew-paschall **Website:** andrewpaschall.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

I am a hands-on Salesforce Architect with 14 years of experience building web-based business applications. I specialize in technical Salesforce roles that utilize my strong presentation and facilitation skills, obtaining stakeholder acceptance by understanding and delivering the right strategic vision, and driving the difficult conversations necessary to execute business strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• **Proficient:** Salesforce, JavaScript, JSON, APIs, APEX, LWC, SLDS, Node.js, jQuery, SOQL, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, Blockchain, Agile, Jira, DevOps; **Exposure:** Mulesoft, Genesys, PHP, Java

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce Development Manager | Allstate Identity Protection | Remote

Feb 2021 – Present

- Build, manage and mentor a high-performing team of 5 Salesforce developers and system administrators
- Maintain hands-on development of key features while performing security review and code review of the team
- Deliver live product demonstrations, technical Q&A, and roadmap communication to C-suite stakeholders
- Develop a program vision while advising and articulating program/project strategies on Salesforce platform
- Spearheaded redevelopment of legacy web application in use by 1,500+ clients, resulting in 20+ new features, reduction of 60% in save/load time and 15% operation time
- Build relationships with internal/external customers, manage expectations and negotiate solutions to complex problems with both the customer and third-party partners

Salesforce Solutions Architect | <u>Allstate Identity Protection</u> | Remote

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Technical lead on team implementing Sales/Service/Community Clouds and Lightning Experience
- Spearheaded functional solution architecture, proof-of-concepts, and gave 20+ live demos to Executive team
- Developed and launched call center applications in Salesforce using Lightning Web Components, Custom Object design, Apex, JavaScript, SLDS, REST APIs, MuleSoft (middleware), and Genesys (telephony)
- Facilitated continuous interaction between users, development and QA teams throughout the SDLC, resulting in a 95%+ testing success rate
- Developed NetSuite ERP integration using Salesforce LWC, Apex, and Mulesoft to sync client payment data
- Implemented a Salesforce-native Contract Lifecycle Management solution (Conga CLM) to house all contract processes, templates, signing, maintenance and SLAs on the Salesforce platform

Salesforce Solutions Architect | Shellback Semiconductor | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2018 – Mar 2019

- Led and completed company-wide implementation of Salesforce Lightning over 6 months. Tools included Custom Object Design, LWC, Visualforce, Flows, Process Builder, SOQL queries, Data Loader and Apex triggers
- Built rich, highly performant applications using Lightning, Apex, and LWC JavaScript frameworks
- Authored business requirements document for Salesforce re-implementation: led requirements gathering sessions, requirements analysis, solution assessment and validation, use cases and interface mock-ups
- Reduced quarterly forecast error by more than 45% via data analysis and custom Salesforce reporting

User Experience Director (UX) | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2013 - Dec 2017

- Responsible for the design, planning, configuration, programming, delivery and maintenance of the company's public website, mobile app, Salesforce CRM, and desk.com support portals
- Managed Salesforce integrations with Hubspot, Marketo and the company's proprietary technology platforms
- Salesforce developer and systems administrator for over 300 users
- Led all UX/UI design for the company's mobile/tablet application for iOS, Android and mobile web
- Automated Marketing processes via configuration and customization of Salesforce reports, dashboards, triggers and workflows

Lead Web Developer | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2011 - Apr 2013

- Overhauled the company website using modern HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript standards; generated 80% more leads via email capture forms, reduced bounce rate by 30%
- Implemented open-source mapping tools to replace the company's existing proprietary application, saving more than \$40,000 per year
- Designed interactive help system and training documentation; reduced customer support calls by 30%

Web Developer (Freelance Consulting) | Cleartorch, Inc. | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2006 - Apr 2011

- Provided full-stack web development and marketing automation solutions to small to medium size companies across the U.S., primarily servicing the Financial Services, Healthcare and Higher Education industries
- Technology included HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress and Drupal
- Define business requirements, user stories and personas
- Create sketch, wireframe, prototype and visual mock-ups
- Conduct UX research with real customers, present findings and make recommendations
- Advocate for web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability
- Conduct website performance testing and network configuration to optimized load times
- Use SEO tools and applications to assist with Google search engine rankings
- Work with backend engineers and IT analysts to see projects through to completion

EDUCATION

Certified Salesforce Platform Developer I Certified Salesforce Platform App Builder Certified Salesforce Administrator **B.A. English,** *Arizona State University*